Lord, love a duck.
Hey, Jenny, you have a hand.
I can't open it.
Move back, dear.
Oh, blimey.
Call his head.
Mr. Partridge.
Hey, Mr. Partridge.
Now
what's the trouble?
Can't open the blinking door.
Come out.
Do you hear me?
This is Victoria Station.
It's funny.
Some drunk sleeping it off.
Some gent's
traveling first class.
Hey, Jim, let's
have the old ladder.
Yes, sir.
Open that window.
I can't budge
it, Mr. Partridge.
Budge is the word.
You'll have to smash it then.
Right.
Mr. Partridge, there's...
Hold it!
There, there...
Run for help!
Fetch the police!
Don't stand there gaping!
This must be the place.
Yes.
You'll have to wait here.
But I'm not gonna let you
go in a place like this alone.
You must, really.
I'll be all right.
This meeting is
now called to order.
The unfortunate death in a train
of one of our members,
Mr. James Murphy,
who departed this
life by his own act
while of unsound mind,
has necessitated this meeting.
That's what you
say, Mr. Merrydew,
but how do you know?
A verdict of death by
suicide was returned tonight.
This is the second occasion
that we have been
brought together
by the mishaps to our members.
The first being the passing
away by natural causes
of the late Colonel Forrester,
whose charming daughter
so gracefully honors us
with her presence here tonight.
It is agreed in
the pact drawn up
and formally attested
to by its founders,
that should the grim reaper
overtake one or more,
the interest of the
deceaseds in the society
will be divided equally
among the surviving members.
It is also provided
for in the pact
that Miss Forrester becomes
a participating member.
Consequently the interests
of the late James Murphy
will be divided equally
among the seven of us.
I move that my fee for the
necessary legal representation,
funeral expenses, and a
modest urn for the ashes,
be defrayed by our organization.
I understand from the widow that
he expressed a
preference for cremation.
I second that.
All those in favor
will please signify
by raising their hands.
Mr. Wilson.
Mr. Baker.
Mr. Dearing.
Mr. Pyke.
Ah Yet?
Good.
Has any provision
been made for the widow?
- None.
- I presume
that we can stretch
a point in her favor.
Emphatically no!
Things are complicated
enough as they are!
Why did he want
to kill himself?
Have you ever met his wife?
No.
No?
Well, I have.
A pest if there ever was one.
We can attribute
his death solely
to the general deficiencies
of one Annabelle Mary Murphy.
What would you
deduce from this?
Obviously, an attempt to
convey secret information.
Could you decipher it?
I could not.
Nor could you.
Would you like to bet?
Certainly.
How much?
A shilling.
My time is too valuable.
The answer will be
found in a large book,
because the numbers are large.
I'd suggest the Bible.
A client, Watson.
- Where?
- The widow
standing under the streetlamp.
A widow?
Would you like to bet on that?
Of course.
Well, I'm not going down
on the street to ask her.
Ah, won't be necessary.
She's made up her mind.
So you deduce
at a distance, eh?
Not in this case.
I recognized her features.
She's a Mrs. Murphy.
Her husband was
murdered three days ago.
You mean the man that
was found dead in a train?
Exactly.
Come in.
A Mrs. Murphy to see you, sir.
Mr. Holmes, I'm in
such a mess, such a mess.
My husband up and died
without leaving me
as much as flip and a bit.
It's a crying shame, Mr.
Holmes, that's what it is.
Sit down and try
to compose yourself.
Cut off without a farthing
by an ungrateful
good for nothing.
Me, at my time of life.
No dirty dog had a better wife.
I waited on him hand to mouth.
Stood by his side
morning, noon, and night,
and what does the stinker do?
He ups and Kills his self,
and leaves his money to a trust.
And Mr. Merrydew.
Yes, and there's another
stinker if I never saw another.
Won't even let me
have a sixpence.
He won't even let me have
a ha'penny, Mr. Holmes.
Thaddeus Merrydew, the lawyer?
Yes, the thieving hound.
The dirty rat!
One moment.
You were married how long?
Five blessed long years.
Previous to your marriage,
your husband served in the Army?
- You knew him?
- Of him.
He got his discharge in China?
Yes, that's right.
Then you married?
Yes, and I gave up
everything, Mr. Holmes.
You ask the proprietor of
the Black Sow he'll tell you.
It was me that made
that pub what it was.
And your husband had money?
Barrels of it,
and when he wanted more,
he used to come up
to London and get it.
It was that, that took him to
London when killed himself.
How do you know?
Well, Jim comes into my room.
I was in bed with a piece of
cucumber rind around me head
trying to cure an headache.
He had a letter in his hand.
"See you, Peg," he said.
That was his pet name
for me when he was drunk.
"I'm going up to London."
Did you read the
contents of the letter?
Oh, it wasn't no letter.
It was just a piece of doggerel.
Watson, make a note of
Mrs. Murphy's address.
232 King's Cross Road.
Then you'll undertake
me, Mr. Holmes?
I'll take up your case.
Mind you, it'll
have to be for love.
Love?
For nix.
I've noticed how you
like working for nothing.
My interest is to bring
the criminal to justice.
Oh, nevermind about justice.
Nevermind about the crime.
All I want is my
husband's lawful money,
and I want you to slap
that thieving lawyer's face
right across between
his greasy fat chops.
Goodnight, Mr. Holmes.
I'll be seeing you,
and thank you kindly.
Goodnight, Mrs. Murphy.
Deep water, Watson.
She needs some
shady lawyer, not you.
- Think so?
- I'm amazed
that you're wasting
your energies
on such a morbid trifle.
Who is this Merrydew?
London's most dangerous crook.
The king of blackmailers.
A gliding, slimy,
venomous snake.
Once in his power,
he'll squeeze and squeeze
until he's drained
his victims dry.
More than once I've
had my net around him,
but so far he's managed
to wriggle his way out.
But the time has come, Watson.
The time has come for
Mr. Thaddeus Merrydew.
And now, Miss
Forrester and gentlemen,
this concludes the meeting.
I would like to have
a word with you alone.
I sincerely trust
no further accidents
will happen to occasion
another meeting.
You never can tell.
Are you going my way?
Which way do you go?
I go the other.
That leads to a dead end.
That's the way I go.
Goodnight, then.
Goodnight.
You must never
mention anything
that transpired at
this meeting tonight,
or even that this
meeting was held.
I saw a young man standing
on the corner as I came in.
Yes, my fiance.
He brought me here, and
he's waiting for me.
Then you're thinking
of being married.
Yes.
I wouldn't, if I were you.
That is, at least until
you've consulted me.
- But why?
- I can't explain.
In a short time this society
will no longer exist.
Until its affairs are winded up,
it would be most unwise
for you to marry.
Your father would
not have wished it.
What had my father to
do with these people?
Didn't he ever tell you?
No.
Then I must
respect his silence.
Remember,
not a word to a living soul.
He's after me.
He's after me!
Captain Pyke!
Dead, shot through the heart.
You wait here.
What is it?
What's happened?
Are you hurt?
Someone...
Look it disappeared!
What does it mean?
The murderer must've
had an accomplice
and removed the body!
We must call the police.
No, no, the police
will be here soon enough.
We mustn't become involved.
But it's murder.
As you respect
your father's memory,
you must preserve
a strict silence.
Not a word.
Come.
The body was pulled
out of the Thames
at 5:00 a.m. in the
Limehouse district.
The autopsy shows
that death was caused
by a bullet through the heart.
The features that you
see are unrecognizable,
caused possibly by the
battering of the head
against the wharf where
the body was found.
The widow identified the
body by means of that ring.
A very rare, and very
beautiful ring, Lestrade.
There isn't the
slightest doubt
the deceased is Captain Pyke.
The clothes were identified,
initials on the collar
and on the shirt.
Further identifications are
contained in these letters
that were found in the clothing.
Where is the widow?
We asked her to wait.
She's in the adjoining room.
Mrs. Pyke?
Yes.
You are?
My name is Sherlock Holmes.
When did you last see
your husband alive?
We dined together last
night at the Savoy Grill.
He left me shortly
after nine o'clock.
I never saw him again.
You are staying?
At the Savoy.
You've been in
London how long?
About a week.
And you live where?
At the Grange Schuberness.
When your husband left you,
did he inform you
where he was going?
No, but I fancied it was
on a matter of business.
He was man very
precise in his habits.
When midnight came,
and there was no sign of him,
I became rather alarmed.
Midnight would be
a late hour for him?
Very.
As the time went on,
I became more and more worried.
At last I informed the police.
An hour ago, I received
a message to come here,
where I identified the
body of my poor husband.
By the ring?
Yes.
Did he always wear a ring?
That one, yes.
I gave it to him
when we were married.
That would be?
About six years ago in China.
It is an heirloom
belonging to my family,
and it has been handed
down for generations.
I see.
Permit me to express my
sympathy for your great loss.
Thank you.
Is that all?
By the way, should
it become necessary,
shall I communicate with you
at the Grange or the Savoy?
Through my lawyer.
His name?
Mr. Thaddeus Merrydew.
Good morning, Mr. Holmes.
Well, what do you make of it?
Murder, unquestionably.
- Is that all?
- That's all I have to say.
What do you think?
I think that the
lady is a liar.
You.
It's not possible!
What do you want with me?
The papers are full of
the Pyke murder mystery.
It seemed to me particularly
senseless and futile.
There was no motive.
No motive?
Peer deep down in the black
heart of Thaddeus Merrydew,
and you'll find a motive.
You don't mean to suggest
that he had anything
to do with it, do you?
I suggest nothing.
Come in.
Inspector Lestrade
to see you, sir.
Mr. Holmes, Dr. Watson.
What's the matter
you look worried.
Worried, I'm up to my neck.
- Again?
- Before I can begin
to finish one case, I'm
plunged into another.
That's the penalty
of being smart.
You came to see
me professionally.
Well, unofficially.
I see, heads you
win, tails I lose.
There's been a bad
business during the night.
An old gentleman.
You'll find it a
bit of a puzzler.
You mean you found
it a bit of a puzzler.
We've left everything
in status quo,
hoping you'll favor
us with an opinion.
Dead?
Murder?
Suicide.
Come, Watson,
the game is afoot.
He was well known
as a stamp collector.
Very interesting.
What is it, Holmes?
That leads out to the garden.
Seldom used to judge
by the rusty hinges.
Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
You can see that I have
left everything untouched.
If a heard of
buffaloes passed along,
it couldn't be a greater mess.
You can take a smoke.
Thank you, sir.
What do you think?
There's been murder done,
and the murderer was a man.
He was in the prime of life,
six feet in height,
has small feet,
wears square toed boots,
limps slightly on the left foot,
and smokes Trichinopoli cigars.
Well, if it was murder,
how was it committed?
The assassin was in the house
before his victim arrived.
He hid in the recess
behind the window.
While there, he smoked a cigar.
He fired a shot,
which hit the victim on
the back of the head,
and then dragged the body
to where you found it.
He left, and returned
some while later
to fire a second shot.
This time through the mouth.
You'll find the mark of a boot
clearly imprinted on
the congealed blood.
What was his object?
To obliterate the
effect of the first shot.
Hoping, by so doing,
to transfer the crime
from that of murder,
to one of suicide.
Bullet number one you will find
in the wall on the
farther side of the room.
The other will be found
embedded in the body
of the murdered man.
Come, Watson.
We mustn't keep Mr.
Merrydew waiting.
Mr. Holmes is
still waiting, sir.
How long has it been, now?
Fully two hours, sir.
That's as it should be.
You may show him in now.
Very good, sir.
Mr. Holmes, this
is indeed a pleasure.
I'm sorry to
have kept you waiting,
but I had to digest my lunch.
This is my friend and
partner, Dr. Watson.
How do you do?
A glass port, gentlemen?
Thank you, no.
Cigar?
Thank you.
Be seated, gentlemen.
I represent
Annabelle Mary Murphy.
Charming lady.
I'm empowered to
act on her behalf.
Congratulations.
As you are doubtless aware,
her husband came to a
premature and sudden end.
Tsk, tsk, tsk, dear, dear.
My client is
under an impression
that certain monies
belonging to the deceased
are being unlawfully
withheld from her.
By who?
By you.
And you believe
this delightful lady?
I'm paid to find out.
An angry woman
is hard to pacify.
So I thought that an
amicable discussion
with you would put me in
possession of certain facts,
with which I could
prove to my client
the absurdity of her claim.
I see.
Is that all?
That is all.
Dear, dear, you're
not smoking my cigar.
You refuse to assist me.
My dear, Mr. Holmes,
I have neither the information
nor the authority.
You see, until a few days ago,
I was not aware that your
distinguished client existed.
In my profession, I
deal with many cases,
impartially and
legally, without coming
into personal contact
with my client.
It won't do, Mr. Merrydew.
Anything else?
May I trouble you
for a pencil and paper?
Help yourself.
Mr. Busybody Holmes.
By the way, I
think you should know
that another client of yours
met his death last night.
Mr. Malcolm Dearing
found murdered.
Good day, Mr. Merrydew.
Come, Watson.
Cold blooded monster.
Well, I've given him
something to think about.
Did you see what I saw?
- His feet.
- What about them?
Well, they were small feet.
And the boots.
Well, well?
Were square toed!
Squared toed!
- Really?
- Yes.
And did you remark
the brand of cigar?
Cigar?
Trichinopoli.
It was stenciled in big
letters on the top of the box.
Was that all you observed?
Was there anything else?
A hundred things.
Among them the
cipher to the code.
A large book, Watson.
I saw no Bible.
Would you call Whitaker's
Almanac a large one?
Yes, indeed.
In that book will be found
the message of the numbers.
Mr. Holmes.
Mrs. Pyke.
Holmes, what did you write
on that sheet of paper?
A long shot in
the dark, Watson,
but it hit a bullseye.
Miss Forrester
lives here, I believe.
Tell her that Mr. Merrydew
wishes to see her.
Mr. Thaddeus Merrydew and hurry!
Mr. Merrydew calling
to see you, Miss.
Miss Forrester.
You're looking charming as ever.
I see you received my flowers.
Thank you.
I sent them to soften the
unexpectedness of my visit.
You've come about the
murder of Captain Pyke?
No.
Have the police
been pestering you?
- No.
- I was fortunate enough
to keep your name out of it.
Have you seen today's papers?
Shocking, shocking.
Poor old gentleman.
This is a very wicked world
we're living in, Miss Forrester.
This will necessitate
another meeting.
That's why I came
myself to tell you.
Safer.
Too many eavesdroppers.
Busy bodies
concerning themselves
with other people's business.
The same time, the same
place, tomorrow night.
Oh, please don't ask me to go
to that dreadful place again.
Well, unfortunately, in
this case I'm a servant
carrying out instructions.
You've nothing to worry about.
Not a thing.
Not a thing in the world.
Oh, mm, this is my...
Mr. Stanford, Mr. Merrydew.
Remember.
I seem to see you everyplace.
Who is that man?
He's my lawyer.
Well, I remember seeing
him the other night.
What's he doing here?
Oh, please don't begin
that all over again.
But, Eileen, surely
I have a right to know.
Oh, John, I'm so miserable.
It's something that
concerned father.
Just before he died,
he sent for me.
I remember his words.
"On my death you'll find
yourself well provided for.
"You'll be rich.
"Remember this name."
He repeated it twice.
"Merrydew.
"Should he communicate with
you follow his instructions.
"For through him will
come this inheritance."
And the meeting
three days ago?
Began the fulfillment
of father's words.
I think I'm beginning
to understand.
I thought I saw...
John!
He was a black bearded
man, ill dressed.
Looked like a tramp.
How tall?
Quite tall.
Could you keep Miss
Forrester under observation
without her knowing it?
I don't understand.
Is Eileen in danger?
In great danger.
You were wise in
coming to see me.
Should anything unforeseen
occur, get in touch with me.
Go to her.
Remember, get in touch with me.
We are getting on, Watson.
I'm glad to see you
in a more cheerful mood.
We've
done remarkably well.
I'm pleased.
I Admit I could do with
a little explanation.
I too feel a little curious.
I considered the claims
of Whitaker's Almanac.
As I suspected,
the large number
represented the page,
the second, the small
number, the column,
and the other figure
is the message.
You'll find it
decoded on the table.
"Meeting of Scarlet Ring,
"Tuesday, Limehouse M."
Merrydew?
Possibly.
Tomorrow will appear
in the personal column
of the "Daily Telegraph”
a second message.
A request for information.
- Your message?
- My message.
And the next step?
The need of fresh air
will take me in the
country tomorrow.
In the meantime,
relaxation, music.
I hope I won't bore you.
Not if you make it soft.
Bah, things are getting
worser and worser.
I hear tell as though
they'll get more worser
before they gets less worser.
Same as I, say.
That were a worry bad
business about Captain Pyke.
A worry bad business.
Same as I say.
I hear tell as
how the Old Grange
is going under the hammer.
Lock, stock, and barrel.
Same as I say.
And I almost broke
this old back of mine,
a weeding that old garden.
And to look at it now,
you'd think I'd spent
all me time in here.
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
Morning, morning.
How far is the Grange from here?
Some will tell you four miles,
and some will tell you five.
But I say it's more than
four and less than five.
Is there any means of
getting there beside walking?
Bless your heart, yes,
sir, I've an old trap.
I'll harness up Old Caesar,
and Old Willy here
will drive you over.
Yeah.
Will you take
anything to drink?
Wouldn't come amiss.
Scotch.
Scotch and splash.
Put a bottle on the
table with some glasses
and a siphon of soda.
Coming, sir, coming.
Lord, love it, it feels
good to be busy again.
You're a godsend to him, sir.
He hasn't had a paying
customer for a long time.
I'll have the trap
on in a jiffy, sir.
Before you can
say Jack Robinson.
Help yourself.
Thank you, sir.
Just a little drop, sir.
Say when.
When.
Well, here's to your
very good health, sir.
Ah, I feel like a new man, sir.
Well, and now give
the new man a drink.
Righto, sir.
When.
Here's to your very
good health again, sir.
Good health.
Were you born in these parts?
Ah, I've never
seen none other.
Worked for the Pyke
family all me life,
till I got tired of working.
Got this old back ache
from weeding their
plaguey old garden.
Then you would remember
the late Captain.
And his father,
and the old gentleman
afore his father.
See that dent?
That belongs to Captain Pyke.
A mark caused possibly
by the imprint of a stone.
And right you are, sir.
Many a good licking
young master Robin got
for chucking stones at me, sir.
Sounds as though the
young man was somewhat wild!
Wild?
He was a holy terror.
Ready and waiting, sir.
I've harnessed up Old Caesar
and he's raring to go.
You must tell me some
more on the way over.
Better bring the bottle.
Righto, sir.
Scotch is sure good
for the backache.
Keep the change.
Oh, thank you, sir.
And call again, sir.
Steady, Caesar, steady.
He's hard to handle when
he's raring to go, sir.
You were saying?
You can't make English gentry
out of the heathen
Chinee, no how.
Not in these parts.
Very difficult, I imagine.
When the Captain was alive,
did he stay here often?
Until last Tuesday,
we ain't seen nothing on him
till close nigh onto two years.
Shall we have one, sir?
You take two.
Righto, sir.
The old back feels
better already, sir.
Magic.
There's the Grange now, sir.
Looks a trifle
the worse for wear.
Any servants there now?
Well, naught in what you
might call real servants, sir.
There's Daft Dolly.
Daft!
And, well, you might have
to be to keep that place.
I kept it for 30 years.
Stop a moment.
Whoa, Caesar.
I'll walk the rest of the way.
I'm in a hurry.
Wait here for me.
I won't budge an inch.
I beg your pardon.
Is your mistress in?
No, sir.
Where is she?
London town.
I understand that
this house is for sale.
I may wish to buy it.
I'll look it over!
That's mistress.
Such a good looker.
Such eyes.
She walks like a cat.
Such a figure.
Such a fine bit of goods.
An English lady make
her look like nothing.
Buzz.
Mistress sleeps here.
Aren't you feeling good?
It's my heart.
Water, quick!
Just a minute! Just a minute!
Drink this.
I'm dying.
Telephone for a doctor.
Oh, no, we haven't got
any phones in the house!
Then go for one.
Doctor is a good
five miles away.
Fetch him hurry, hurry!
Run!
All right!
I'll run, I'll run!
It's so kind of
you to have come.
Knowing my late husband
as intimately as you did,
I felt I could turn
to no better person
to help me through
this trying time.
Well, you know,
anything I can do.
You are very nervous today.
Well, I can't help it.
Look at my hands.
You know, I'm
trembling all over.
There.
That'll stop the
rattling, at any rate.
My late husband always spoke
of you in the warmest terms,
and you know the high regard,
in which, I have
always held you.
Oh, have you?
Can you doubt it?
You are the only one who
knows my husband's affairs.
Everything has been left in
the most terrible disorder.
My house in the
country will be sold.
I wonder, if you
could spare the time?
Yes?
You could be my
guest over the weekend,
and we could go through
his papers together.
Really, now, with pleasure.
I could do with a
bit of a change.
We could drive down.
Would tonight be possible?
Tonight? No.
You see, I got an
important meeting tonight.
Then tomorrow.
Tomorrow.
May may I make a
little confession?
You know, Mrs. Pyke,
I've always admired
you tremendously.
Who's that?
Baker.
Oh, it's you, is it?
Who did you think it was?
Where are the others?
I'm the first one here.
There's a rat among us.
Yes, and he's facing
me seated on a chair.
It's a lie!
Someone has given away the code.
"Anyone supplying information
"concerning the Scarlet Ring
"will be rewarded.
"Apply, Sherlock Holmes,
"221A Baker Street."
It's one of us that's certain.
We can leave the girl out of it.
It can't be that dumb Chinaman.
There remains you,
myself, and Merrydew.
Well, it's not me, on my oath!
Or me, I swear it!
Then it's...
If I thought that snake was
double crossing me, I'd...
Well, it's getting
on my nerves!
It's like
living a nightmare.
First Murphy, then
Pyke, then Dearing.
Who'll be next?
Psst.
Suppose someone was to supply
information to Sherlock Holmes?
Then it would all come out.
No, no, Holmes is
different from the police.
He protects clients.
Holmes works with the police.
What's in the back of your mind?
I want a fighting chance!
I want to live!
This suspense is
getting on my nerves!
It's killing me!
What suspense?
Well, pray be seated, gentlemen.
I overheard your conversation.
It's most illuminating.
Yeah, we are not going on.
No?
And why not, pray?
I don't want to
die like Murphy.
Nor be found dead like Pyke.
No, perhaps
you'd like to spend
the rest of your
lives in prison, hmm?
No, my friends, crime
brought together,
and by crime you
will stick together.
Gentlemen, in a few more days
the Scarlet Ring
will cease to exist.
We'll cease to
exist, you mean.
I have just received work
from the agent in Antwerp
that the plunder has
finally been disposed of.
This time next week,
the principal will
be in my hands.
A small unimportant matter
of some one million pounds
to be divided equally among
us, 200,000 pounds apiece.
200,000 pounds.
And meanwhile?
You waited for five years
what's a matter of a few days?
Yeah, what guarantee is there
we'll be alive to receive it?
None.
Of course, if it were requested
of your life without the money,
it might be arranged.
How?
Letter in the form
of a deed of gift
relinquishing your
right to any benefits
accruing to the Society.
And give up 200,000 pounds?
It might ensure your life.
I'd see you burn first!
Shh, not a word.
Well, Miss Forrester,
this is a pleasure.
Come in.
Won't you sit down?
And now to business.
Miss Forrester and gentlemen,
again I have the pleasure of
presiding at this meeting.
Hello?
One moment.
A Mr. Stanford.
Yes?
Where?
Oh, thank heavens you've come.
I followed her here and
phoned you immediately.
She went through the side door.
There were four others.
The lawyer, two white men,
strangers, and a Chinaman.
When it comes, it
won't come from the sky.
Oh, shut up!
Cold?
I'm on fire.
Life's worth more
to me than money!
Yours may be, mine isn't.
Shall we walk to the
station together?
No, no, you go ahead.
She's inside!
They've left her inside!
Gas!
Quick, the door!
Eileen!
- Darling.
- Get her in the fresh air!
Darling.
You came in the nick of time.
Get her home.
Don't let her out of your sight.
Guard her.
Hey!
I must see him!
Save me! Save me!
Speaking as a medical man,
it is extremely dangerous to run
at your age and
with your weight.
Could I have a glass
of water, please?
Sit down.
Oh, thank you.
I must apologize
for bursting in like
this, Mr. Holmes.
I'm Dr. Watson.
I don't know when Mr.
Holmes will be back.
Please wait.
Thank you.
Come in.
Sit down.
Cigarette?
Any luck?
Too bad.
I have here the securities.
Easily negotiable
for a million pounds.
The Chinaman Ah Yet is
devoted to his mistress.
Doubtless a generous
present will satisfy him.
On account of Holmes, I
cannot impress upon you
too sufficiently the
necessity for speed.
Everything must be finished
tomorrow night at the Grange.
I will make all
the arrangements.
You've got to
help me, Mr. Holmes!
If you don't, I'm a doomed man!
Not 10 minutes ago,
an attempt was made on my life!
You see, I live on Ebury Street.
I was on me way there.
I was about to cross the road,
and some instinct
made me leap back.
And as I did, a car,
driven with terrific speed,
and coming on the wrong side
of the road, whizzed by me.
How I escaped was a miracle.
Did you by any chance see
the occupant of the car?
Yes, as it flashed by me,
I caught a glimpse
of the driver.
A black bearded man.
Is there anyone who would
benefit by your death?
Yes, four persons.
You see, Mr. Holmes,
there's an estate
to be settled up,
and if I should go out,
well, they get my share.
Is any one of them capable
of committing a crime?
Yes, three of them!
How much is your
share of this estate?
200,000 pounds.
Naturally, you would
wish to live to enjoy it.
When were you in China last?
I was never in China.
Come, come, sir.
In the tattooing
above the right wrist.
Oh, that, that
was done in England.
You must be mistaken.
That particular yellow is
to be found only in China.
What made you come to me?
Well, you see,
Mr. Holmes, I've...
Well, I'd heard of
your reputation.
How did you know my address?
Aren't you here in answer
to my advertisement?
Were you not returning
from Limehouse?
Are you not a member
of the Scarlet Ring?
Is it not a fact that
three of your members
have met with very sudden ends,
and you're terrified lest
their fate befall you?
Why, you must be
the devil himself!
Answer me!
Yes, Mr. Holmes.
But I'm helpless.
I'm up against some power
that no precaution
can guard against!
Go straight home and lock
yourself in your house.
But it's very old
and easily broken into.
Have you a cellar?
Bomb proof.
Hide there.
On second thought,
we'll see you to Ebury Street.
Take a revolver, Watson.
Mr. Holmes, do you
think there's any hope?
Obey my instructions
implicitly,
and I can promise
you almost a chance.
Tomorrow, leave town.
You see, Mr. Holmes,
I had intended that.
You see, I know a little
place in the country,
very secluded, miles
away from anyplace.
It belongs to the widow of
an acquaintance of mine.
The lady is an Oriental.
An Asiatic.
As a matter of
fact, she's Chinese.
Mrs. Pyke.
When you arrive at the
Grange near Schuberness,
you'll probably be given
the room next to the lady's.
You'll find a door
connecting the two rooms.
Keep it locked.
Arrive there neither before
nor later than nine o'clock.
On your arrival,
pretend a headache.
Pretend one?
Oh, Mr. Holmes.
Go straight to your room,
and if you value your life,
don't open the door.
Baker!
They got him too.
Poisoned.
Wait here, says he, for me,
and that's the
last I seed of him.
A regular queer one,
free with his money.
Same as I say.
He must've been a
pickle when he was a lad.
Dolly ran all the way
to fetch Dr. Smallwood,
and she and Smallwood
nigh burst a blood vessel
trying to get to him.
And when they found
him, he wasn't there,
and nary a one of them
ever set eyes on him again.
Same as I say.
Company.
Evening, gentlemen, evening.
Up you get, Willy,
make way for the gents.
Good evening, gentlemen.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
Would you take
anything to drink?
Wouldn't come amiss.
Scotch and splash?
How did you know, sir?
Thank you, sir.
Give your orders, gentlemen.
Put a bottle on the
table, and some glasses,
and a siphon of soda.
Righto sir.
Bottle of whiskey,
four glasses, siphon.
Gentlemen.
- There you go.
- Righto.
Hurry up, hurry up, it's
for the tall gentleman here!
Four glasses.
There you are.
Here you are, sir.
There you are, sir.
What brings you gentlemen
around these here parts?
This friend of mine belongs
to the medical profession.
A patient of his has escaped.
An old gentlemen,
a very dangerous character.
That's the reason for
all these wardens.
An old gentlemen,
wearing a cape,
stoops a bit, big in the belly?
- You've seen him?
- Have I seed him?
Yes, sir, and Dolly at
the Grange seed him,
and Dr. Smallwood
oughta seed him,
but he never set eyes on him!
As sure as I'm
standing here, sir,
he sat right there!
It was the day before yesterday.
Doctor, we're
on the right set.
- Say when.
- When!
Well, here's to your
very good health, sir.
Another beer?
Thank you very kindly, sir.
Pay the bill, Watson,
and take care of this gentleman.
Come along, what'll you have?
Well, here's hoping
that we get him.
Who?
Dash my buttons if I know.
My mind has never
been in such fog.
It's time to leave.
Gregson should
be there by now.
We'll have the Grange
so well surrounded
a cat couldn't get through
without being seen.
Come along, men.
Mr. Holmes, something
terrible has happened.
Miss Forrester has disappeared.
Disappeared, but I
told you to guard her.
But I couldn't
understand your telegram.
Telegram, what telegram?
Instructing me to
meet you at Dover.
- Are you mad?
- I don't know.
I'm almost insane with worry.
Goon.
Well, I arrived at Dover
and suspected it was a hoax.
I returned to
London immediately.
Fortunately, I
have a racing car.
Arriving there, I went
straight to Eileen's house.
She'd gone.
A maid told me that she'd
left in the early afternoon
with a strange woman.
A Chinese woman?
Yes.
I called you, but you'd left.
When I gave my name
to your housekeeper,
she told me where
I could locate you.
Oh, Mr. Holmes, what could
have happened to her?
Where could she be?
Come, Lestrade, there's
not a moment to lose.
Mr. Holmes is late.
Are you sure
you're not mistaken?
I had written instructions
to bring you here.
You saw them.
Perhaps the fog.
Well, he's certain to be here.
If not tonight,
then tomorrow morning.
Who's that?
Strange.
Stop!
You open that door,
and I'll choke the
life out of you!
Mr. Wilson, have
you lost your reason?
Tell him if he
opens that door,
he'll never live
to open another!
Who is it?
Telegraph wire.
Telegraph for Miss Forester.
I'll give it to her.
Thank you.
Good news”?
- Excuse me.
- What is it?
What is it?
What does it mean?
I'm going to bed.
Miss Forrester,
when you go to your room,
lock your door.
And keep it locked.
What's the matter?
I'm rather chilly.
Who's that?
It's me, sir.
Did you deliver the telegram?
- Yes, sir.
- To Miss Forrester herself?
I gave it to one lady
to give to the other, sir.
Thank you, goodnight.
Goodnight, sir.
Let me go to her.
Wait.
I'll never do it again.
What?
Stand about all
night without a flask.
Look, Holmes, over there.
Drop your gun.
Well, Inspector?
I've checked up on all points.
No one could have
slipped through.
Goodnight, my dear.
My bedroom is just
across the corridor.
If you should want
me for anything,
don't hesitate to call me.
Thank you.
Goodnight.
Mr. Wilson, are you in bed?
Yes, yes.
Sorry.
Goodnight.
Who's that?
Gregson.
He's here, came by boat.
- When?
- 15 minutes ago.
Why didn't you
let me know sooner?
It's this fog.
Our men lost their bearings.
Watch the front of the house.
Come, come!
All right, you stay here.
Very good, then.
I thought you
would never come.
It's this cursed fog.
Where's the girl?
At the end of the corridor.
Good.
Wilson?
He's locked his door.
Well, get him out.
Offer him any inducement.
He's in the house.
It's Eileen!
That's Eileen!
Mr. Wilson, quick,
Miss Forrester,
something terrible has happened!
Eileen.
My dear.
Eileen, my darling,
are you all right?
Help.
Murder!
Help!
Break it down.
Help! Help!
Holmes!
Holmes, are you all right?
Quite all right.
Thank you, Watson.
Take them downstairs.
As I suspected.
Captain Pyke.
You are charged
with the murders
of James Murphy, Malcolm
Dearing, and William Baker.
And this woman?
As an accomplice.
Take them away.
I saw him Killed.
You saw him
pretend to be killed.
It was he who attacked you.
He was shot.
No shot broke that window.
He broke it himself.
But the blood.
Animal blood, on a sponge.
Merrydew, of course,
was in on it.
Mr. Holmes, there's
a second man outside.
Came by car.
I thought it my
duty to detain him.
Bring him in.
Well, well, well, Mr. Holmes.
This is indeed a surprise.
What are you doing here?
Well, surely a man has a
right to visit his own house.
I own the mortgage
on this place.
I've invited some friends
down for the weekend
to discuss some business.
It won't do, Merrydew.
Arrest him.
Well, this is rather
a high handed procedure.
What are the charges, Holmes?
The gravest possible.
That of being accessory
to the murders
of James Murphy, Malcolm
Dearing, and William Baker,
and with the attempted
murder of Jabez Wilson
and Miss Eileen Forrester.
Hm, rather a tall indictment.
I think you'd better
have the bracelets.
May I help you?
I've more than enough
evidence to hang you.
I think not.
But then, who can tell?
I say, who can tell?
This will mean
promotion, Lestrade.
I'm very grateful
to you, Mr. Holmes.
But how you did it beats me.
Simple enough.
Simple.
Simple?
By the examination
of the footsteps
in the garden of
Mr. Dearing's house,
I was tolerably certain of
the murderer's description.
He'd answered in every
particular to that of Pyke,
furnished me later
by the war office.
I was equally certain that
the body in the morgue
was not that of Pyke.
You will remember the ring.
There was no mark to
indicate that it had remained
on that finger for a
period of six years,
as stated by his mistress.
His wife, you mean.
Mistress, Watson.
Mistress.
Well,
you ought to know.
And the Scarlet Ring?
Perhaps you will
remember the disappearance
of the Mandarin's gems
in China some years ago.
Perfectly.
To realize on gems
of international repute
would be a ticklish matter?
Very, they'd have to be
broken up piece by piece,
and then disposed of
carefully and slowly.
Exactly.
The Scarlet Ring was
formed by the instigators
of the original crime to
protect the receiving end.
And what was Pyke's motive?
Greed.
The last survivor would
become the recipient
of the entire booty.
I think it will
be found that Pyke
was the original ring leader.
But Mr. Wilson could furnish
us with an answer to that.
Not one word.
We shall never
forget you, Mr. Holmes.
Rather not, sir.
You must invite
me to the wedding.
Perhaps you'll give me away.
I appreciate the compliment,
but I never give a lady away.
Except sometimes professionally.
Come, Doctor.
They'll send you
when they need you.